<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lei Si</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Lei Si</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marsvegetables.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Mars Landscape with Blender: My Experience Today</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/blog/marslandscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/blog/marslandscape/</guid><description>Today, I created a Mars landscape using Blender. The result was stunning, and I am thrilled with how beautiful the final product turned out to be. I incorporated a rover into the scene, which I downloaded from NASA, to add a sense of realism to the environment. Using Blender allowed me to unleash my creativity and develop my skills in 3D modeling and visualization.</description></item><item><title>2D Quadrilateral Meshes Quality Improvement</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/quadmesh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/quadmesh/</guid><description>Quadrilateral (or quad) meshes generated by various remeshing and simplification methods for input models with complex structure and boundary configurations often possess elements with minimal quality, which calls for an optimization approach to improve their individual elements’ quality while preserving the boundary features. Many existing methods either fix boundary vertices during optimization or assume a simple boundary configuration. In this paper, we introduce a new quality improvement framework for 2D quad meshes with open boundaries.</description></item><item><title>Hexa/Quad Mesh Quality Study</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/hqview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/hqview/</guid><description>we present a new quality visual analysis system for 3D hexahedral (hex) and 2D quadrilateral (quad) meshes. Our system allows users to focus their attention on areas with poor quality elements without being distracted by the large elements in the mesh model through an aggregated quality glyph. Our system also explicitly highlights places with overlapping elements that are typically hard to see with existing visualization tools. In addition, we display boundary error information in three different forms to support its detailed inspection, which is often ignored by existing visualization tools.</description></item><item><title>Hi, I am Si, Lei (斯磊)</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/home/</guid><description>Ph.D. student,
Department of Computer Science,
University of Houston,
Houston, TX, USA
Résumé</description></item></channel></rss>