<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lei Si</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Lei Si</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 11:37:43 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marsvegetables.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hybrid Base Complex</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/hexdomviz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/hexdomviz/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hex-dominant mesh generation has received significant attention in recent research due to its superior robustness compared to pure hex-mesh generation techniques. In this work, we introduce the first structure for analyzing hex-dominant meshes. This structure builds on the base complex of pure hex-meshes but incorporates the non-hex elements for a more comprehensive and complete representation. We provide its definition and describe its construction steps. Based on this structure, we present an extraction and categorization of sheets using advanced graph matching techniques to handle the non-hex elements. This enables us to develop an enhanced visual analysis of the structure for any hex-dominant meshes.We apply this structure-based visual analysis to compare hex-dominant meshes generated by different methods to study their advantages and disadvantages. This complements the standard quality metric based on the non-hex element percentage for hex-dominant meshes.
Moreover, we propose a strategy to extract a cleaned (optimized) valence-based singularity graph wireframe to analyze the structure for both mesh and sheets. Our results demonstrate that the proposed hybrid base complex provides a coarse representation for mesh element, and the proposed valence singularity graph wireframe provides a better internal visualization of hex-dominant meshes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Mars Landscape with Blender</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/blog/marslandscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/blog/marslandscape/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, I created a Mars landscape using Blender. The result was stunning, and I am thrilled with how beautiful the final product turned out to be. I incorporated a rover into the scene, which I downloaded from NASA, to add a sense of realism to the environment. Using Blender allowed me to unleash my creativity and develop my skills in 3D modeling and visualization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://marsvegetables.github.io/blog/marslandscape/overview_mars.png" alt="Rendered Overview">
&lt;img src="https://marsvegetables.github.io/blog/marslandscape/blenderOpt_mars.png" alt="Blender Operation Interface">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2D Quadrilateral Meshes Quality Improvement</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/quadmesh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/quadmesh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quadrilateral (or quad) meshes generated by various remeshing and simplification methods for input models with complex structure and boundary configurations often possess elements with minimal quality, which calls for an optimization approach to improve their individual elements’ quality while preserving the boundary features. Many existing methods either fix boundary vertices during optimization or assume a simple boundary configuration. In this paper, we introduce a new quality improvement framework for 2D quad meshes with open boundaries. Our framework aims to optimize the configuration of an embedded polygon constructed based on the one-ring neighbors of each interior vertex. A feature-preserved boundary optimization is also introduced based on the angle configuration of the individual boundary vertices to further improve the quality of the boundary elements. Our framework has been applied to a number of 2D quad meshes with various boundary configurations and compared with other representative methods to demonstrate its advantages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hexa/Quad Mesh Quality Study</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/hqview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/hqview/</guid><description>&lt;p>we present a new quality visual analysis system for 3D hexahedral (hex) and 2D quadrilateral (quad) meshes. Our system allows users to focus their attention on areas with poor quality elements without being distracted by the large elements in the mesh model through an aggregated quality glyph. Our system also explicitly highlights places with overlapping elements that are typically hard to see with existing visualization tools. In addition, we display boundary error information in three different forms to support its detailed inspection, which is often ignored by existing visualization tools. Furthermore, multiple views are provided to support a multi-level analysis of the local mesh configuration at places with low quality elements. To demonstrate the effectiveness of our system, we have applied it to analyze the quality of different mesh models and compare the performance of a couple of mesh generation and mesh optimization algorithms for quadrilateral and hexahedral meshes, respectively.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ThreeJS Practice</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/threejs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 11:37:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/threejs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/mrdoob/three.js">Three.js&lt;/a> is a JavaScript 3D library, and builds only include a WebGL renderer but WebGPU (experimental).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://marsvegetables.github.io/projects/threejs/webgl_tonemapping.html">Practice example 1&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hi, I am Si, Lei (斯磊)</title><link>https://marsvegetables.github.io/home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marsvegetables.github.io/home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ph.D. candidate,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Department of Computer Science,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>University of Houston,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Houston, TX, USA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://marsvegetables.github.io/home/LeiSi_CV.pdf">Résumé&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>